<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Wild Bush Luxury</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 06:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/cropped-Arkaba-Walk-Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184390017</site>	<item>
		<title>Evolution or Insect?</title>
		<link>/evolution-or-insect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom. Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9427" class="elementor elementor-9427" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-53f8da9 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="53f8da9" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-dd966f9" data-id="dd966f9" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-18b3892 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="18b3892" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p><!-- wp:video {"id":8640} --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:video --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom.</p>
<p>Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, however two theories have been posed; an evolutionary mutation perhaps, producing sports e.g. different flower colour, from genetic changes or the flower heads could have been attacked or galled by an insect such as a thirp or wasp, who have had a long evolution between the gall maker and the plant.</p>
<p><div class="envira-gallery-feed-output"><img class="envira-gallery-feed-image" tabindex="0" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_8220-1.jpg" title="Acacia Tetragonophylla" alt="" /></div></p>
<p>A very exciting and stunning find for us on Arkaba, we shall be watching how they evolve!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eradicat Program</title>
		<link>/eradicat-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 05:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4"></video></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare 30 000 sausages for the 2020 eradicat feral cat bait trial. The eradicate programme is an attempt to control feral cat populations in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park and the adjoining Arkaba Conservancy. Arkaba has been involved in this trial for the past few years. If deemed successful, this new technique of cat control will be rolled out across the state and potentially even country wide. Arkaba Conservancy (64 000 acres) acts as an important southern corridor for the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park, with the Conservancy’s conservation efforts partnering with those of the National Park to increase the habitat area and viability for local populations of threatened native species.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In 2014, Idnya (Western Quoll) and Virlda (Brush tailed Possum) where reintroduced into the Flinders Ranges. Both mammals had become locally extinct due to the compounding effects of habitat destruction and the arrival of feral carnivore species (cats and foxes). On Akaba, feral cat management has and continues to involve cage trapping, spotlight shooting and the control of feral rabbit populations. These efforts whilst playing an important role are yet to deliver a knockout blow to local feral cat populations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Historically, baiting has not been an overly successful control method for cats as they prefer to catch their own prey and consume them differently to feral foxes and dogs. The eradicate baiting trials have now been ongoing for a number of years in an attempt to investigate the effectiveness of a 1080 (toxin derived from native flora) sausage bait that has been specifically designed to be more appealing to feral cats.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Prior to the baits being dropped across the National Park and Arkaba, feral cats and Western Quolls have been caught and collared (with radio collars) to monitor their movements as well as the effect of the bait. Past years have shown that the bait has been highly effective on cats with no known deaths to the quolls, who like other native animals have a natural evolved tolerance to the native toxin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">The current results of the eradicate programme for 2020 have shown that 4 of the 9 collared cats have died and none of the 16 collared quolls have been affected, this is certainly deemed as a success.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Whilst participating in the baiting day, Arkaba staff had the unique opportunity to see three Western quolls be released after capture and collaring (as per the video where Charlie Eager is release one of the quolls). Seeing these beautiful and rare native marsupials bounce off through the bush was an experience that we hope with continued cat control all future visitors and generations will one day have the chance to enjoy.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4" length="9187499" type="video/mp4" />

		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</title>
		<link>/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After 5 years of drought, Arkaba Homestead has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots. It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>After 5 years of drought, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank">Arkaba Homestead</a> has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots.<br> <br>It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry kangaroos, so the change was in order. Our main objective was to ensure the Arkaba garden reflected our greater purpose, to conserve and encourage our natural environment to flourish, with a little flare of course. As the long standing homestead fence was pulled down, local designer and Arkaba field guide, Melissa Robertson, was tasked with finding a way to bring the Arkaba ethos right to the homestead’s back door.<br> <br>With a Bachelor Degree in Design Arts and armed with 8 years’ experience running her successful design business, I Am Melissa, in Melbourne, it was only fitting that Melissa Robertson took on the role of Arkaba Landscape Designer. Melissa strived to create a design with meaning and greater purpose, taking her inspiration from the land, to mirror the surrounds of the stunning Flinders Ranges, whilst creating a sustainable landscape.</p> <img loading="lazy" width="300" height="248" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Mel-300x248.jpg" alt="" style="font-size: inherit;"></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>Arkaba’s newly designed garden is modelled off the aerial view of the vast ranges that tower around Arkaba and included the well-known geological anomaly, Wilpena Pound. As you walk out into the back garden you are greeted with a rustic central fire pit (being that of Ikara, Wilpena Pound), paying homage to the dreaming stories of the country. The ABC Range and Heysen Range are stretches of meticulously placed rocks which run outward from that towards Arkaba Creek, whilst the majestic Elder Range runs south toward the front of the homestead.&nbsp;The garden will provide another medium through which Wild Bush Luxury and Arkaba carry out their mission to not only conserve their environment but to inspire, educate and reconnect guests with the bush.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was pivotal, with sustainability in mind, that the Homestead Landscape design focused on utilising resources from around the property, to reflect the unique micro-environments at Arkaba Conservancy. Each geological range that is referenced is inspired by the rock formations of that specific range paired with the vegetation that is found in these landscapes. Guests will, literally, have a taste of what Arkaba has to offer in their back garden.<br>Melissa was particularly passionate about utilising native vegetation from Arkaba, propagating a variety of species to be planted out. This meant reintroducing specific natives like the Sturt Desert Rose (Gossypium sturtianum), which have not been seen on Arkaba for some time and encouraging indigenous threatened species like Slender Bell Fruit (Codonocarpus pyramidalis) to flourish.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not only will the garden represent a&nbsp;‘land that once was’&nbsp;but it will reflect the species that miraculously manage to thrive in this arid region of Australia. The benefit of utilising and encouraging the native flora from this region, means that it is naturally adapted to surviving with minimal rainfall – which is essential as we sit at the end (hopefully) of a five-year drought. This will ensure our garden is naturally sustainable and will need very little input from our human hands. To supplement this we pay homage to our farming heritage, utilising recycled farming materials throughout the design. From the path edging made out of old fencing pickets to old Cypress Pine fence posts as retaining walls for our outdoor dining space, ensuring the Arkaba Landscape project was truly designed with a holistic approach.<br>&nbsp;<br>It truly has been a huge effort by our guides, head chef and general manager at the homestead during these extraordinary times, to achieve this vision. This however is not the end of our gardens story, we are sure as the landscape naturally changes around us, our own backyard will evolve along with it and we are all looking forward to seeing what happens next!</p></p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9185</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</title>
		<link>/short-beaked-echidna-trains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Works]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nicola-Anne Jack recently joined our spirited field guiding team at Arkaba in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. She was warmly welcomed by a Short-beaked Echidna train sighting on her second day on the ground and she was kind enough to recall and share the moment with us. Here goes &#8230; It was always going to be [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/short-beaked-echidna-trains/">Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1182" class="elementor elementor-1182" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-3c3f0d87 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="3c3f0d87" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-340ff05e" data-id="340ff05e" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-78ce2805 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="78ce2805" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p style="text-align: center;">Nicola-Anne Jack recently joined our spirited field guiding team at Arkaba in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. She was warmly welcomed by a Short-beaked Echidna train sighting on her second day on the ground and she was kind enough to recall and share the moment with us. Here goes &#8230;</p>
<div style="text-align: center;">It was always going to be a new and foreign experience heading to the Land Down Under to visit the Arkaba Conservancy in South Australia. Having spent the last three years working in the wilderness of Botswana the prospect of possibly relocating myself to the Australian Outback was somewhat daunting, especially with my limited knowledge on this incomparable environment with its extremely rare hopping fauna and fire loving flora.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Little did I realise that my visit to Arkaba had in stall for me one of the most fascinating and unique sightings I had and probably would ever see.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">The sighting occurred around 3pm as our Landcruiser ventured back from a visit to Elders Trail Camp.  As we drove the red sandstone slopes of white Cyprus Pine (Callitris glaucophylla) I was staring out the window when I noticed the movement of three small balls ambling in a wobbly line along the bottom of a steep slope. They walked in a trail one after the other, each following the first over the dusty soil. I surprisingly recognised this creature straight away, but I am sure this was only due to all the Australian documentaries I had recently watched! They were very peculiar looking with small rounded bodies covered with course hair and spines. Their snouts were prominent, slender and elongated. To me they looked like a hybrid of two familiar animals; a hedgehog and a very large shrew! As I stared on I could still not believe what I was seeing. My understanding was that this small marsupial which lays eggs – one of only five species in the world to do so – was a rare sighting.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Stop! Echidna’s, echidna’s!’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Brakes went on and both Bradley and Charlie heads whipped around searching the slopes to our left to try locate what I was seeing.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Are they in a line’, was Charlie’s first verbal response.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">In a line?  Since when do you ID an animal or spot an animal easier if it is in a line?</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Yes?’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘It’s an echidna train!’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">A what? I later discovered that an ‘echidna train’ is the term used to describe the mating behaviour of echidna’s (Tachyglossus aculeatus) during the winter season. During the mating season an oestrus female will release a pheromone which can attract up to ten males into close proximity. As each individual male finds the female it will follow her hence you get these trains of male echidna’s, in diminishing size order, following one female. Over several weeks the males will jostle each other out of the train until the most dominant suitor remains. This is the male which will mate with the female. It was unclear if our sighting was the tail end of this fascinating behaviour or only the beginning but as it stood at this point there were two males contending for the affection of the female.</div>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":9201,"sizeSlug":"full"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-group">
<div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<p class="has-text-align-center">We clambered out the car and quietly snuck up on this rare sight. I can safely say we did not do the best job of this as all three echidnas’ instantly responded to our approach. The female took full advantage of the situation and ambled up the slope away from us and both the males pursuing her. Maybe a welcome relief? The two remaining males demonstrated their best anti-predator behaviour which entailed using their robust digging claws to dig themselves into the soil beneath a large pine leaving only their exposed spiny backs as defence. We settle down to watch the two males, hoping they would feel relaxed enough to come out of their soil havens and walk around for us. As we waited Charlie informed us of some rare and specialised adaptions of this species including the presence of an egg tooth on the 10-day old naked translucent puggle (the name given to young echidna’s) and their ant and termite diet facilitated by a long sticky tongue. As we listened to Charlie the pair of males slowly emerged from their holes sniffing the air with their strange long snouts and then slowly (or maybe it was fast for an echidna) ambled away in opposite directions.   What a fascinating uniquely Australian experience! I am looking forward to the next one. To join us at <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba</a> for an outback Australian adventure with <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">purpose</a> call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Stay%20at%20Arkaba">email us</a> today.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:group --></p>
<p><!-- wp:group --></p>
<div class="wp-block-group">
<div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"> </div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:group --></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/short-beaked-echidna-trains/">Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outback Adventure</title>
		<link>/outback-adventure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The journey started weeks before I arrived in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges for the Arkaba walk. The excitement of the adventure that I was about to embark on. Leaving my busy city life, I packed my bags and head for the outback to reconnect. As I stepped off our private plane in Hawker, I took in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-adventure/">Outback Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">The journey started weeks before I arrived in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges for the Arkaba walk. The excitement of the adventure that I was about to embark on. Leaving my busy city life, I packed my bags and head for the outback to reconnect.</p>
<p>As I stepped off our private plane in Hawker, I took in a deep breath smelling the fresh country air. Taking in my surroundings, I had never seen such vibrant colours of earthly oranges and reds. There was no denying that I was in the Australian outback. We enjoyed our continental breakfast as we learnt about the land on our way to Wilpena for the start of our walk.</p>
<p>After a few hours of walking through the changing scenery of Wilpena Pound, we approached the edge of Arkaba Conservancy. A birder got our attention making a gesture to come over quietly. Over on the rock face he points out the movement and handed me his binoculars. It&#8217;s a yellow-footed rock wallaby. How exciting! I knew these guys were near threatened so this sighting was a true blessing.</p>
<p>We were welcomed into camp with a warm smile, a face towel and a delicious fresh juice. The perfect combination to feel right at home. I was way too eager to head to bed that evening. Taking our guides advice, I pulled my swag bed from under cover exposing it directly under the night sky. Upon gazing up, I was instantly in awe, the abundance of stars was absolutely breathtaking. The peace and serenity being a true luxury only possible to experience in such a remote location.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Even though I have grown up in Australia, there is still something special about seeing kangaroos amongst the acient landscape in the outback. We made a game of guessing which type of kangaroo we were spotting. We eventually learnt to tell the difference between euros, western greys and reds.. with the help of our guide of course.</p>
<p>Coming over Arkaba hill on the final day with the homestead in sight brought on a range of emotions. On one hand we were all wishing the walk to be longer, on the other we were so excited to see where we were going to call home for the evening. Waiting with a fresh juice, closely followed by a G &amp; T our guides did not disappoint with a warm welcome back to the homestead.</p>
<p>Spending four days walking with the group, we got to know each other pretty well. Everyone had their own story what brought them to experiencing the Arkaba walk. Some had dreamed of visiting the Flinders since they were young and for others it was serendipitous. What we all left there with was the mutual feeling that there was something so uniquely special about Arkaba and we will remember the experience for a life time.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-adventure/">Outback Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</title>
		<link>/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photogarphy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past 36 years Richard I’Anson has travelled the world amassing a substantial and compelling collection of images of people and places in more than 90 countries on all seven continents. He is one of five photographers selected for the National Geographic Channel television series Tales by Light now showing on Netflix. We asked him why keeps coming [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/">Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">Over the past 36 years <a href="https://richardianson.com/2013/05/22/bamurru-photo-safari-images/">Richard I’Anson</a> has travelled the world amassing a substantial and compelling collection of images of people and places in more than 90 countries on all seven continents. He is one of five photographers selected for the National Geographic Channel television series <em>Tales by Light</em> now showing on Netflix. We asked him why keeps coming back to Bamurru Plains. Here’s what he said;</p>
<p><strong>You can’t predict what’s going to happen or script settings when photographing wildlife in the wild. Can you share any hot tips in getting good wildlife shots in such a dynamic environment?</strong></p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Concentrate your efforts to early morning and late afternoon when wildlife is most active.</p>
<p>Make sure you’ve got the right gear for the subject matter you’re photographing, the location and what you’re hoping to achieve. Typically, a DSLR with a telephoto zoom is the way to go. You’ll need a lens with a focal length of at least 300mm and for birds at least 500mm. A 100-400mm zoom lens is great, add a 1.4x extender and you’ve got a range from 100-560mm.</p>
<p>Make sure you’ve practiced, and ideally perfected, your technique as the most interesting moments of action, such as birds taking off or landing, happen very quickly and you don’t want to be messing around with your gear at the crucial moment.</p>
<p>A good guide, and in the case of Bamurru a good airboat driver, are crucial to getting you into the best position by considering the direction of the light, the background and the potential for action. Let alone spotting potential subjects in the first place.</p>
<p>Finally, you need to be patient. Wildlife shots that go beyond the simple identification picture take time and commitment, so patience is a key part of wildlife photographers’ makeup. But when it all comes together the hours of watching, waiting and practicing will be well rewarded with memorable, and often, one-off images.</p>
<p><strong>You’re a world traveller through and through. Can you share your thoughts on what makes Bamurru unique and worth travelling across the country, or indeed the world, to experience?</strong></p>
<p>It is just that! Bamurru is unique. There is no where else like it. The outback location, the ambience of the lodge and safari cabins, the great food and the adventure of getting about the floodplains on airboats. And that’s even before you start considering the wonderful photography on offer every time you step outside.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a favourite moment from your last safari?</strong></p>
<p>There are always so many favourite moments. The lilies were absolutely incredible this year, I’ve never seen them so dense. We came across a comb-crested jacana, one of the hardest birds to photograph, protecting the eggs that she had laid on a waterlily leaf, so she wasn’t going anywhere. And a perennial favourite is heading back to the lodge on an airboat at sunset sipping a red wine and reflecting on how amazing it is just to be there.</p>
<p><strong>If these kind of group trips aren’t usually your thing, would you recommend giving this one five days of your precious time?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely! Bamurru is special and the photography safari is pretty special too, which is why we have so many returning guests. You’ll be joining a small group of enthusiast photographers keen to improve their photography skills in a unique setting offering so many opportunities to photograph landscapes, wildlife, birds and indigenous culture that you’ll probably want to return too. And I’ve never yet had a group up at Bamurru that isn’t great company.</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">If you&#8217;d like to speak to someone about our <a href="https://www.bamurruplains.com/top-end-wilderness-photo-safari/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Top End Wilderness Photo Safari</u></a> with Canon Master Richard I’Anson 27 April &#8211; 1 May 2019 call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:bamurru@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20the%20Richard%20I%27Anson%20Photo%20Safari!">email us</a> today.</div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/">Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brush Tail Possum Spotted</title>
		<link>/brush-tail-possum-spotted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/finance/?p=1213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week was an incredibly exciting one for us with confirmation of what were once extinct Brush Tailed Possums (or Virlda in Adnyamathanha). Captured by one of our conservation cameras at our wildlife viewing hide, the blurry (and furry!) guy in the bottom right is being watched by a thirsty kangaroo. Brush tailed possums are believed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/brush-tail-possum-spotted/">Brush Tail Possum Spotted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Last week was an incredibly exciting one for us with confirmation of what were once extinct Brush Tailed Possums (or Virlda in Adnyamathanha). Captured by one of our conservation cameras at our <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wildlife viewing hide</a>, the blurry (and furry!) guy in the bottom right is being watched by a thirsty kangaroo.</p>
<div><img src="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/assets/blog/Brush%20Tail%20Possum/Possum.JPG" alt="" /></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Brush tailed possums are believed to have gone locally extinct in the 1940&#8217;s, with habitat degradation and predation by feral predators such as cats and foxes, being some of the suspected causes for its disappearance. Reintroduction alongside the Western Quoll (Idnya in Adnyamathanda) took place in Arkaba&#8217;s neighbouring Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park back in June 2015.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">With this individual safely being able to travel over 20km from the release site in search of food, water (and hopefully mating partners), it&#8217;s a significant sign good things are happening and our environment is recovering as a result <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">conservation programs</a> being carried out by the Arkaba team. Conservation work that is actively supported by each and every guest who has ever experienced Wild Bush Luxury with us at Arkaba.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">To learn more about <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arkaba</a> or to experience conservation in action, call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Stay%20at%20Arkaba">email us</a> today.</div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/brush-tail-possum-spotted/">Brush Tail Possum Spotted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Outback Christmas</title>
		<link>/an-outback-christmas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://staging.arkabaconservancy.com/?p=2685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s nothing quite like an Aussie Christmas – gorging on fresh seafood, summer salads and pavlova piled high with fruit; leaving out a cold tinny for a boardshort clad Santa; sliding down waves or sand dunes instead of snow; and hustling for the best spot in the loungeroom to watch the Boxing Day test match [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-outback-christmas/">An Outback Christmas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="wppb-builder-container" class="wppb-builder-container">
<p>There’s nothing quite like an Aussie Christmas – gorging on fresh seafood, summer salads and pavlova piled high with fruit; leaving out a cold tinny for a boardshort clad Santa; sliding down waves or sand dunes instead of snow; and hustling for the best spot in the loungeroom to watch the Boxing Day test match while leftovers are passed around.<br><br>While the majority of Aussie families flock to the coast to escape the heat over the festive season, the summer months in the heart of our nation is when the spirit of the outback truly comes alive.<br><br>Along with stunning vistas taking on new dimensions and the priceless travel-brag ammo that is simply sticking out an inland Chrissy, some of Australia’s favourite native species are also out to celebrate in this delicate and interconnected ecosystem.<br><br>Here’s what you can expect from an outback Christmas.</p>



<p><strong>Glorious sunsets to light Santa’s way</strong><br>Increased dust in the outback over the drier periods can deliver some of the best sunrises and sunsets of the year. As the sun moves lower towards the horizon and the light has to travel further, strong summer beams catch the individual dust particles along the way and result in a spectacular red and orange sky. A great time of year for world-class photography opportunities, whether you’re a novice or a pro.</p>



<p><strong>Happy twitchin’</strong><br>The festive season in the outback is a party playground for flocks of visiting nomadic birds like budgerigars and cockatiels. Chasing summer thunderstorms to seek water, the sky can be a vivid spectacle of colour as flocks become more concentrated at dwindling water holes as storms become fewer and farther between. Catch them at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&#8217;s widlife viewing hide</a>, Arkaba Creek, sliding rock spring and salty spring.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Incredible wildlife sightings</strong><br>You’ll come across increased sightings of goannas, dragons and skinks as they bask in the open sun. Late breeding seasons bring brushtail possums and their pouched young into the landscape and, excitingly, you might even catch a glimpse of an endangered Western Quoll. Presumed extinct across the majority of the nation, Western Quolls have been spotted at our&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba Conservancy</a>&nbsp;in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. We have worked tirelessly on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">conservation</a>&nbsp;and re-introduction work for the past 10 years, resulting in sightings on the property. It’s our very own Christmas miracle.</p>



<p><strong>Summer storm bonanza</strong><br>While the outback is known for the pretty stable forecast of dry and hot, Christmas time brings some of the most intense storms and downfalls of the year – which is warmly welcomed by the land and the locals. Quiet creek beds can suddenly find themselves overflowing, bringing along a flurry of life and activity as flora and fauna make the most of the cool respite. It&#8217;s a dramatic experience that leaves you in no doubt about the magnificence and wrath of mother nature, leaving the land lush and well-fed in the glistening aftermath.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To experience Wild Bush Luxury at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&nbsp;</a>next&nbsp;Christmas (and all year-round) call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild Bush Luxury</a>&nbsp;specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20Arkaba!">email us</a>.&nbsp;This post first appeared in Fairfax.&nbsp;</p>
</div><span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-outback-christmas/">An Outback Christmas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Great Gear for a Great Walk</title>
		<link>/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since 1930,&#160;Paddy Pallin&#160;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since 1930,&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.paddypallin.com.au/" target="_blank">Paddy Pallin</a>&nbsp;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9236" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Photo by Lachlan Gardiner</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy was a gear maker and innovator. Through each generation of business, Paddy Pallin’s products have kept people comfortable and safe so you have the confidence to head out and explore the world.</p>



<p>Frank Austin Pallin, who we all know and love as “Paddy”, was always at the forefront of Australian conservation. His efforts were further cemented in launching the Paddy Pallin Foundation, which began simply as an informal way to give funds to suitable causes, and to educate those who had an active interest in the environment. Whether they loved plants and animals, bushwalking, canyoning, skiing, climbing or camping – Paddy and his customers at the time knew we had something on our hands worth protecting.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9233" width="750" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg 950w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-300x91.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-768x234.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-610x186.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 950px) 100vw, 950px" /><figcaption>Founder, Frank Austin Pallin</figcaption></figure>



<p>Since its inception in 1975, The Paddy Pallin Foundation has supported a myriad of environmental campaigns including the Tasmanian Franklin River Fight, the conservation of the Glossy Black Cockatoo and the Great Koala National Park. Over the years, Paddy Pallin (in conjunction with the Paddy Pallin Foundation) has partnered with various environmental conservation groups to help develop initiatives to promote and conserve our natural Australian environments and protect our native animal and plant species.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Franklin-River.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9234" width="750" height="400"/><figcaption>Franklin River, Tasmania. Photo by Mark W, a winner of Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest to raise funds and awareness for the &#8220;Give a Dam&#8221; campaign in NSW</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9235" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Great Koala National Park, one of the various conservation initiatives Paddy Pallin has committed to supporting</figcaption></figure>



<p>In support of these environmental values, Paddy Pallin has committed to donating 20 cents to an environmental cause every time one of their customers says “no” to a shopping bag. This initiative spans the country, with customers from coast to coast finding creative ways to haul their gear out of the store!&nbsp; Last year alone, with the help of sustainably minded customers Paddy Pallin was able to divert over 37,000 shopping bags from landfill. This year, Paddy Pallin is supporting a conservation project titled ‘Protect Australia’ that strives to safeguard Australia’s native plant and animal species.</p>



<p>Seeking out community initiatives to support, Paddy Pallin gets involved on both a nation wide and small local scale. Most recently, Paddy Pallin put its forces behind the Wild Rivers campaign, now going by the name ‘Give a Dam’. Raising both funds and awareness through a photo contest to show case the location’s natural beauty, this campaign focused on protecting the greater Blue Mountains area from flooding due to the proposed raising of the Warragamba Dam.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9237" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-610x915.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption>Photo from Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest. Photo by Joel J.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy Pallin as an organisation prides itself on offering the highest quality outdoor gear from around the world that’s brought to you with reliable, expert customer service and intertwined environmental priorities allowing consumers to have a voice and an impact with their purchases.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Favourite Watering Hole</title>
		<link>/our-favourite-watering-hole/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. The Hide at Arkaba is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed-vimeo wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Arkaba | Australian Natives at The Hide" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/283589764?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="1150" height="647" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank"><em>The Hide</em></a> at <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/">Arkaba</a> is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, from Red Kangaroos to Little Eagles, and it gives you a once-in-a-lifetime, up-close-and-personal experience with some of the outback’s wildest characters (sometimes even complete with a brawl!)<br> <br>Galahs are one of the most prominent and easily identifiable bird species in all of Australia. With their beautiful rose-colored bodies and noisy chattering, they are an unmistakable Australian icon. As seen here, this time of year you can find them flocking in large numbers before pairing off in the spring for mating. Similar to other bird species, Galahs pair for life and both sexes incubate eggs and care for young in the nest (cue: aw!). Once mating season is officially underway, Galahs can be found throughout Arkaba’s 60,000 acres nesting in tree hollows lined with their plucked down feathers. Though nationally Galahs have a high chick mortality rate (averaging 50% mortality per nest), we have seen an inspiring increase in chick survival at Arkaba as a direct benefit of feral cat management and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank">conservation</a>.<br> <br><strong>Did You Know:</strong> Though virtually every Australian can identify Galahs, very few can distinguish between males and females. The trick to identifying sex is in the EYE of the beholder – literally! Female Galahs have a light brown to pink iris, while males have a dark brown to black iris. Can you spot the sexes in this video?</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Arkaba is uniquely positioned on the cusp of the territory ranges of three species variations of Australian Ringneck Parrots. All three variations mate without discrimination and hybridize seamlessly, making for unique and exciting spottings for sharp-eyed bird watchers who can discern subtle plumage variations. Ringnecks are opportunists and will feed on whatever is available – fruits, seeds and even insects. Like Galahs, Ringnecks are readying to pair off for the mating season, where they too can be found in tree hollows. Luckily unlike Galahs, Ringnecks have impressive fledgling survival rate at around 75% per nest, and have also benefited from the feral cat management at Arkaba over the last nine years.<br>&nbsp;<br>The word “Arkaba” means “place of hidden water and place of plenty”. Like all the best, our hidden watering hole carefully carved out of Arkaba and Woolshed Creeks brings in a range of characters from the rowdy to the peaceful. You can of course indulge in a beverage of your choice and a spot of morning or afternoon tea at the Hide while rubbing shoulders and sharing a laugh with the locals at Arkaba’s watering hole. It’d be rude not to!<br>&nbsp;<br>To visit Arkaba&#8217;s watering hole yourself, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank">Wild Bush Luxury</a>&nbsp;Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20Arkaba!">email us</a>&nbsp;today!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9244</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
