<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Wild Bush Story &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/wild-bush-story/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Wild Bush Luxury</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 06:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/cropped-Arkaba-Walk-Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Wild Bush Story &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184390017</site>	<item>
		<title>Evolution or Insect?</title>
		<link>/evolution-or-insect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom. Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9427" class="elementor elementor-9427" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-53f8da9 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="53f8da9" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-dd966f9" data-id="dd966f9" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-18b3892 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="18b3892" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p><!-- wp:video {"id":8640} --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:video --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom.</p>
<p>Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, however two theories have been posed; an evolutionary mutation perhaps, producing sports e.g. different flower colour, from genetic changes or the flower heads could have been attacked or galled by an insect such as a thirp or wasp, who have had a long evolution between the gall maker and the plant.</p>
<p><div class="envira-gallery-feed-output"><img class="envira-gallery-feed-image" tabindex="0" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_8220-1.jpg" title="Acacia Tetragonophylla" alt="" /></div></p>
<p>A very exciting and stunning find for us on Arkaba, we shall be watching how they evolve!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Outback Christmas</title>
		<link>/an-outback-christmas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://staging.arkabaconservancy.com/?p=2685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s nothing quite like an Aussie Christmas – gorging on fresh seafood, summer salads and pavlova piled high with fruit; leaving out a cold tinny for a boardshort clad Santa; sliding down waves or sand dunes instead of snow; and hustling for the best spot in the loungeroom to watch the Boxing Day test match [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-outback-christmas/">An Outback Christmas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="wppb-builder-container" class="wppb-builder-container">
<p>There’s nothing quite like an Aussie Christmas – gorging on fresh seafood, summer salads and pavlova piled high with fruit; leaving out a cold tinny for a boardshort clad Santa; sliding down waves or sand dunes instead of snow; and hustling for the best spot in the loungeroom to watch the Boxing Day test match while leftovers are passed around.<br><br>While the majority of Aussie families flock to the coast to escape the heat over the festive season, the summer months in the heart of our nation is when the spirit of the outback truly comes alive.<br><br>Along with stunning vistas taking on new dimensions and the priceless travel-brag ammo that is simply sticking out an inland Chrissy, some of Australia’s favourite native species are also out to celebrate in this delicate and interconnected ecosystem.<br><br>Here’s what you can expect from an outback Christmas.</p>



<p><strong>Glorious sunsets to light Santa’s way</strong><br>Increased dust in the outback over the drier periods can deliver some of the best sunrises and sunsets of the year. As the sun moves lower towards the horizon and the light has to travel further, strong summer beams catch the individual dust particles along the way and result in a spectacular red and orange sky. A great time of year for world-class photography opportunities, whether you’re a novice or a pro.</p>



<p><strong>Happy twitchin’</strong><br>The festive season in the outback is a party playground for flocks of visiting nomadic birds like budgerigars and cockatiels. Chasing summer thunderstorms to seek water, the sky can be a vivid spectacle of colour as flocks become more concentrated at dwindling water holes as storms become fewer and farther between. Catch them at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&#8217;s widlife viewing hide</a>, Arkaba Creek, sliding rock spring and salty spring.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Incredible wildlife sightings</strong><br>You’ll come across increased sightings of goannas, dragons and skinks as they bask in the open sun. Late breeding seasons bring brushtail possums and their pouched young into the landscape and, excitingly, you might even catch a glimpse of an endangered Western Quoll. Presumed extinct across the majority of the nation, Western Quolls have been spotted at our&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba Conservancy</a>&nbsp;in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. We have worked tirelessly on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">conservation</a>&nbsp;and re-introduction work for the past 10 years, resulting in sightings on the property. It’s our very own Christmas miracle.</p>



<p><strong>Summer storm bonanza</strong><br>While the outback is known for the pretty stable forecast of dry and hot, Christmas time brings some of the most intense storms and downfalls of the year – which is warmly welcomed by the land and the locals. Quiet creek beds can suddenly find themselves overflowing, bringing along a flurry of life and activity as flora and fauna make the most of the cool respite. It&#8217;s a dramatic experience that leaves you in no doubt about the magnificence and wrath of mother nature, leaving the land lush and well-fed in the glistening aftermath.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To experience Wild Bush Luxury at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&nbsp;</a>next&nbsp;Christmas (and all year-round) call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild Bush Luxury</a>&nbsp;specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20Arkaba!">email us</a>.&nbsp;This post first appeared in Fairfax.&nbsp;</p>
</div><span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-outback-christmas/">An Outback Christmas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Great Gear for a Great Walk</title>
		<link>/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since 1930,&#160;Paddy Pallin&#160;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since 1930,&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.paddypallin.com.au/" target="_blank">Paddy Pallin</a>&nbsp;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9236" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Photo by Lachlan Gardiner</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy was a gear maker and innovator. Through each generation of business, Paddy Pallin’s products have kept people comfortable and safe so you have the confidence to head out and explore the world.</p>



<p>Frank Austin Pallin, who we all know and love as “Paddy”, was always at the forefront of Australian conservation. His efforts were further cemented in launching the Paddy Pallin Foundation, which began simply as an informal way to give funds to suitable causes, and to educate those who had an active interest in the environment. Whether they loved plants and animals, bushwalking, canyoning, skiing, climbing or camping – Paddy and his customers at the time knew we had something on our hands worth protecting.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9233" width="750" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg 950w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-300x91.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-768x234.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-610x186.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 950px) 100vw, 950px" /><figcaption>Founder, Frank Austin Pallin</figcaption></figure>



<p>Since its inception in 1975, The Paddy Pallin Foundation has supported a myriad of environmental campaigns including the Tasmanian Franklin River Fight, the conservation of the Glossy Black Cockatoo and the Great Koala National Park. Over the years, Paddy Pallin (in conjunction with the Paddy Pallin Foundation) has partnered with various environmental conservation groups to help develop initiatives to promote and conserve our natural Australian environments and protect our native animal and plant species.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Franklin-River.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9234" width="750" height="400"/><figcaption>Franklin River, Tasmania. Photo by Mark W, a winner of Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest to raise funds and awareness for the &#8220;Give a Dam&#8221; campaign in NSW</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9235" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Great Koala National Park, one of the various conservation initiatives Paddy Pallin has committed to supporting</figcaption></figure>



<p>In support of these environmental values, Paddy Pallin has committed to donating 20 cents to an environmental cause every time one of their customers says “no” to a shopping bag. This initiative spans the country, with customers from coast to coast finding creative ways to haul their gear out of the store!&nbsp; Last year alone, with the help of sustainably minded customers Paddy Pallin was able to divert over 37,000 shopping bags from landfill. This year, Paddy Pallin is supporting a conservation project titled ‘Protect Australia’ that strives to safeguard Australia’s native plant and animal species.</p>



<p>Seeking out community initiatives to support, Paddy Pallin gets involved on both a nation wide and small local scale. Most recently, Paddy Pallin put its forces behind the Wild Rivers campaign, now going by the name ‘Give a Dam’. Raising both funds and awareness through a photo contest to show case the location’s natural beauty, this campaign focused on protecting the greater Blue Mountains area from flooding due to the proposed raising of the Warragamba Dam.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9237" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-610x915.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption>Photo from Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest. Photo by Joel J.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy Pallin as an organisation prides itself on offering the highest quality outdoor gear from around the world that’s brought to you with reliable, expert customer service and intertwined environmental priorities allowing consumers to have a voice and an impact with their purchases.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Favourite Watering Hole</title>
		<link>/our-favourite-watering-hole/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. The Hide at Arkaba is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed-vimeo wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Arkaba | Australian Natives at The Hide" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/283589764?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="1150" height="647" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank"><em>The Hide</em></a> at <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/">Arkaba</a> is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, from Red Kangaroos to Little Eagles, and it gives you a once-in-a-lifetime, up-close-and-personal experience with some of the outback’s wildest characters (sometimes even complete with a brawl!)<br> <br>Galahs are one of the most prominent and easily identifiable bird species in all of Australia. With their beautiful rose-colored bodies and noisy chattering, they are an unmistakable Australian icon. As seen here, this time of year you can find them flocking in large numbers before pairing off in the spring for mating. Similar to other bird species, Galahs pair for life and both sexes incubate eggs and care for young in the nest (cue: aw!). Once mating season is officially underway, Galahs can be found throughout Arkaba’s 60,000 acres nesting in tree hollows lined with their plucked down feathers. Though nationally Galahs have a high chick mortality rate (averaging 50% mortality per nest), we have seen an inspiring increase in chick survival at Arkaba as a direct benefit of feral cat management and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank">conservation</a>.<br> <br><strong>Did You Know:</strong> Though virtually every Australian can identify Galahs, very few can distinguish between males and females. The trick to identifying sex is in the EYE of the beholder – literally! Female Galahs have a light brown to pink iris, while males have a dark brown to black iris. Can you spot the sexes in this video?</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Arkaba is uniquely positioned on the cusp of the territory ranges of three species variations of Australian Ringneck Parrots. All three variations mate without discrimination and hybridize seamlessly, making for unique and exciting spottings for sharp-eyed bird watchers who can discern subtle plumage variations. Ringnecks are opportunists and will feed on whatever is available – fruits, seeds and even insects. Like Galahs, Ringnecks are readying to pair off for the mating season, where they too can be found in tree hollows. Luckily unlike Galahs, Ringnecks have impressive fledgling survival rate at around 75% per nest, and have also benefited from the feral cat management at Arkaba over the last nine years.<br>&nbsp;<br>The word “Arkaba” means “place of hidden water and place of plenty”. Like all the best, our hidden watering hole carefully carved out of Arkaba and Woolshed Creeks brings in a range of characters from the rowdy to the peaceful. You can of course indulge in a beverage of your choice and a spot of morning or afternoon tea at the Hide while rubbing shoulders and sharing a laugh with the locals at Arkaba’s watering hole. It’d be rude not to!<br>&nbsp;<br>To visit Arkaba&#8217;s watering hole yourself, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank">Wild Bush Luxury</a>&nbsp;Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20Arkaba!">email us</a>&nbsp;today!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9244</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monet&#8217;s Garden</title>
		<link>/monets-garden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 06:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Words, pictures and moment sketch courtesy of Kerry Lorimer @kersplashhh Artist Claude Monet was famously obsessed with water lilies and, well, it’s hard not to be when carpets of them stretch as far as the eye can see. But when they’re reflected in slightly shimmering water, evoking Monet’s Impressionistic painterly treatment of them… well, photographically-speaking, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/monets-garden/">Monet&#8217;s Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Words, pictures and moment sketch courtesy of Kerry Lorimer @kersplashhh</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Artist Claude Monet was famously obsessed with water lilies and, well, it’s hard not to be when carpets of them stretch as far as the eye can see. But when they’re reflected in slightly shimmering water, evoking Monet’s Impressionistic painterly treatment of them… well, photographically-speaking, I got a bit carried away.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="681" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9253" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1024x681.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-391x260.jpg 391w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-610x406.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">One of the most magical of many enchanted places on Bamurru Plains is what the Bamurru staff rather prosaically refer to as ‘Kingfisher 1’. Around 20 minutes by air boat from the safari lodge is a secret forest of flooded melaleucas, their peeling, shabby-chic trunks submerged in tannin-dark water, sheltering a fairyland of water lilies among them. It takes a few minutes for your eyes to adjust from the glaring sunlight of the floodplain to the shadowy soft light and silence among the paperbarks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="681" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9256" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-1024x681.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-391x260.jpg 391w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1-610x406.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1207-1.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">It’s so still the trees and lilies are perfectly reflected in the water: so perfectly it’s hard to tell the difference between solid and liquid images. It’s mesmerising. And then a zephyr breeze ruffles the water surface, turning the whole scene into an Impressionist masterpiece, so like Monet’s paintings I wonder if his technique was revolutionary or, actually, utterly realistic.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="681" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9254" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-1024x681.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-391x260.jpg 391w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006-610x406.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Bamurru-Kerry-Lorimer-1006.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you&#8217;d like to learn more about our Wild Bush Luxury experience at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.bamurruplains.com/" target="_blank">Bamurru Plains</a>, please call 1300 790 561 or email <a href="mailto:bamurru@wildbushluxury.com?subject=I%27d%20love%20to%20learn%20more%20about%20Bamurru%20Plains!">bamurru@wildbushluxury.com</a> today. Your inner Monet will thank you!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/monets-garden/">Monet&#8217;s Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9251</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</title>
		<link>/arkabas-hide-in-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our new hide is not only a place to see, but to watch wildlife and all the fascinating interactions that occur between species at&#160;Arkaba, our 60,000 acre private wildlife conservany in South Australia&#8217;s Ikara-Flinders Ranges.&#160; Common Wallaroos: (Macropus robustus erubescen) or Euros, belong to the Family Macropodidae. A very common sighting on Arkaba, this adult [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-hide-in-action/">Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Our new hide is not only a place to see, but to watch wildlife and all the fascinating interactions that occur between species at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba</a>, our 60,000 acre private wildlife conservany in South Australia&#8217;s Ikara-Flinders Ranges.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Common Wallaroos: (<em>Macropus robustus erubescen</em>) or Euros, belong to the Family Macropodidae. A very common sighting on Arkaba, this adult female was seen bringing her joey to drink at the hide. This little fellow would be approximately 10 months old and will be fully developed between 18-20 months. Even after this period of independence is reached, the youngster can maintain a very close relationship with its mother. It&#8217;s always fascinating to watch the interactions with other large Macropods such as the sub-adult Red Kangaroo in the background who was chased away on several occasions as he got too close to the joey.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Heading to the hide by Arkaba Creek for a spot of morning or afternoon tea is a chance to observe wildlife being wild.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you would like to speak to someone about our Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Arkaba%20Homestead%20and%20The%20Hide">email us</a>&nbsp;today</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="680" height="449" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9271" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449.jpg 680w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449-300x198.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449-610x403.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></figure>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-hide-in-action/">Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Playtime at Lake Eyre</title>
		<link>/playtime-at-lake-eyre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 07:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Donald Campbell set the world speed record in his Bluebird jet engine car in 1964 clocking 648.7km/hour on the dry salt pans of Lake Eyre. Nearly 55 years later, a very different Lake Eyre is about to appear thanks to floodwaters heading south from Queensland through the Diamantina north of Birdsville. Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre will [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/playtime-at-lake-eyre/">Playtime at Lake Eyre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Donald Campbell set the world speed record in his Bluebird jet engine car in 1964 clocking 648.7km/hour on the dry salt pans of Lake Eyre. Nearly 55 years later, a very different Lake Eyre is about to appear thanks to floodwaters heading south from Queensland through the Diamantina north of Birdsville. Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre will soon transform from a desert fit for racing cars to a water oasis waking spangled perch from hibernation and attracting cormorants, pelicans and other water birds.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Don&#8217;t miss this rare chance to witness Australia&#8217;s second largest inland lake come alive on an air safari from Arkaba.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">With Arkaba&#8217;s 60,000 acre grand scale property as your base, when you stay three immersive days, you have the option of expanding your horizons in the air and take off on an outback air safari over Wilpena Pound and across the salt pans of Lake Torrens before heading further inland to see Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Your air safari will take you over Wilpena Pound and the ancient ramparts of the Ikara-Flinders Ranges including Bunyeroo and Brachina Gorges. Passing over Parachilna Gorge tracking north takes you over open-cit coal fields at Leigh Creek, the outback township of Marree and then the wonder that is Lake Eyre. When it does fill it becomes Australia&#8217;s largest lake, better known as an &#8216;inland sea&#8217; flourishing with bird and wildlife. Breathtaking views and an array of spectacular colours will astound as we track west across the lake towards one of Australia&#8217;s smallest townships, William Creek. The iconic William Creek hotel is the venue for lunch along with the opportunity for a short stroll around the town. Departing south takes you over the Painted Desert, Strangeway Mound Springs, Andamooka opal fields and Lake Torrens. Your experienced pilot will provide commentary throughout and can answer any questions you have along the way.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">One six hour air safari over Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre and all-inclusive three night stay at Arkaba Homestead is $4,170 per person, twin share with a minimum of two people. If you would like to speak to someone about this Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Lake%20Eyre%20Explorer">email us</a>&nbsp;today.&nbsp;</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/playtime-at-lake-eyre/">Playtime at Lake Eyre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9274</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</title>
		<link>/arkabas-little-eagle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This Little Eagle (Hieraaetus morphnoides) was spotted above&#160;Arkaba&#8217;s&#160;homestead garden. This individual might have been hunting rabbits, reptiles or even birds when field guide Charlie managed to snap this picture as it came down to land on an old fence post. This beautiful eagle, along with the larger and more commonly known Wedge-tailed eagle make up [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-little-eagle/">Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">This Little Eagle (Hieraaetus morphnoides) was spotted above&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&#8217;s</a>&nbsp;homestead garden. This individual might have been hunting rabbits, reptiles or even birds when field guide Charlie managed to snap this picture as it came down to land on an old fence post. This beautiful eagle, along with the larger and more commonly known Wedge-tailed eagle make up the only two “booted” eagles in Australia, their feathered legs being one of the features that set them apart from other Australian Raptors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">New evidence suggests that Little Eagles migrate from South to North during the winter months, explaining why we tend to see them more frequently in the summer. One individual was recorded to have travelled as far as 3,000km in a season!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Nesting pairs of this very attractive eagle have been recorded across Arkaba, our private wildlife conservancy in&nbsp;South Australia&#8217;s Flinders Ranges over the past couple of years, with birds preferring to nest in dense, tree lined watercourses with large living trees. Arkaba will continue to be an attractive breeding ground for the Little Eagle, as&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current and future conservation</a>&nbsp;projects continually improve the health of river red gum communities across the conservancy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you would like to speak to someone about the Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399&nbsp;to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20me%20more%20about%20Arkaba">email us</a>&nbsp;today.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="554" height="415" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9281" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2.jpg 554w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></figure></div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-little-eagle/">Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9280</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hanging up our Shirts</title>
		<link>/hanging-up-our-shirts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9289</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What a delightful way to reflect on the Arkaba Walk season that was, with this picture of a rainbow hugging our Elder Range. Come and learn about some of the exciting things that have happened in our region: Lonely Planet has named South Australia as one of the Top 5 regions of the World to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hanging-up-our-shirts/">Hanging up our Shirts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">What a delightful way to reflect on the Arkaba Walk season that was, with this picture of a rainbow hugging our Elder Range. Come and learn about some of the exciting things that have happened in our region:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Lonely Planet has named South Australia as one of the Top 5 regions of the World to visit in 2017 and our region, the Ikara-Flinders Ranges, certainly delivered. We’ve loved being able to share this remarkable landscape with more people, from all walks of life and every corner of the globe, than ever before. The sky has seen a noticable increase in raptor activity with a new active eagle nest very close to the Arkaba Homestead.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">As many of you may have noted, we have experienced a drier season than usual, leading to suberb walking conditions and unbelievably starry nights that stretch endlesslyacross the sky, uninterrupted with your best viewpoint being all wrapped up in our signature star beds.&nbsp;<br>This year an Ikara-Flinders Ranges rock shelter had a chance discovery making it the oldest known site of Aboriginal settlement in arid Australia. The discovery revealed settlement in the region existed a staggering 10,000 years earlier than previously thought and serves as the first reliably dated evidence of human interaction with megafauna! We’re reminded again just how young we are, a short walk through Arkaba&#8217;s landscape clearly illustrates the changes of time the Ikara-Flinders Ranges have seen, the colour of the rocks under our feet, each coming from a different location, a different millennia telling a different story. If only those big old River Red Gum trees could talk!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Walkers are learning how we are breathing native life back into Arkaba. Now 7 years in to our active conservation program, we can see how the land is responding, regenerating, and how native wildlife is returning all the time and in greater numbers. Guests are learning why conservation and saving Australia&#8217;s biodiversity matters, and why our future delivering quality wildlife experiences depends on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">To all of our friends and family of the Arkaba Walk &#8211; Brendon, Charlie and the entire team would like to thank you for walking with us and allowing us to share our love for this incredible place in outback South Australia, Arkaba in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges. Please get in touch any time on&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Arkaba%20Walk%202018">arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com</a>, we&#8217;d love to hear from you. See you for more wilderness walking from 22 March 2018!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hanging-up-our-shirts/">Hanging up our Shirts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9289</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
