<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Conservation &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/conservation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Wild Bush Luxury</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:57:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/cropped-Arkaba-Walk-Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Conservation &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184390017</site>	<item>
		<title>Eradicat Program</title>
		<link>/eradicat-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 05:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4"></video></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare 30 000 sausages for the 2020 eradicat feral cat bait trial. The eradicate programme is an attempt to control feral cat populations in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park and the adjoining Arkaba Conservancy. Arkaba has been involved in this trial for the past few years. If deemed successful, this new technique of cat control will be rolled out across the state and potentially even country wide. Arkaba Conservancy (64 000 acres) acts as an important southern corridor for the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park, with the Conservancy’s conservation efforts partnering with those of the National Park to increase the habitat area and viability for local populations of threatened native species.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In 2014, Idnya (Western Quoll) and Virlda (Brush tailed Possum) where reintroduced into the Flinders Ranges. Both mammals had become locally extinct due to the compounding effects of habitat destruction and the arrival of feral carnivore species (cats and foxes). On Akaba, feral cat management has and continues to involve cage trapping, spotlight shooting and the control of feral rabbit populations. These efforts whilst playing an important role are yet to deliver a knockout blow to local feral cat populations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Historically, baiting has not been an overly successful control method for cats as they prefer to catch their own prey and consume them differently to feral foxes and dogs. The eradicate baiting trials have now been ongoing for a number of years in an attempt to investigate the effectiveness of a 1080 (toxin derived from native flora) sausage bait that has been specifically designed to be more appealing to feral cats.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Prior to the baits being dropped across the National Park and Arkaba, feral cats and Western Quolls have been caught and collared (with radio collars) to monitor their movements as well as the effect of the bait. Past years have shown that the bait has been highly effective on cats with no known deaths to the quolls, who like other native animals have a natural evolved tolerance to the native toxin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">The current results of the eradicate programme for 2020 have shown that 4 of the 9 collared cats have died and none of the 16 collared quolls have been affected, this is certainly deemed as a success.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Whilst participating in the baiting day, Arkaba staff had the unique opportunity to see three Western quolls be released after capture and collaring (as per the video where Charlie Eager is release one of the quolls). Seeing these beautiful and rare native marsupials bounce off through the bush was an experience that we hope with continued cat control all future visitors and generations will one day have the chance to enjoy.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4" length="9187499" type="video/mp4" />

		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</title>
		<link>/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After 5 years of drought, Arkaba Homestead has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots. It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>After 5 years of drought, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank">Arkaba Homestead</a> has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots.<br> <br>It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry kangaroos, so the change was in order. Our main objective was to ensure the Arkaba garden reflected our greater purpose, to conserve and encourage our natural environment to flourish, with a little flare of course. As the long standing homestead fence was pulled down, local designer and Arkaba field guide, Melissa Robertson, was tasked with finding a way to bring the Arkaba ethos right to the homestead’s back door.<br> <br>With a Bachelor Degree in Design Arts and armed with 8 years’ experience running her successful design business, I Am Melissa, in Melbourne, it was only fitting that Melissa Robertson took on the role of Arkaba Landscape Designer. Melissa strived to create a design with meaning and greater purpose, taking her inspiration from the land, to mirror the surrounds of the stunning Flinders Ranges, whilst creating a sustainable landscape.</p> <img loading="lazy" width="300" height="248" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Mel-300x248.jpg" alt="" style="font-size: inherit;"></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>Arkaba’s newly designed garden is modelled off the aerial view of the vast ranges that tower around Arkaba and included the well-known geological anomaly, Wilpena Pound. As you walk out into the back garden you are greeted with a rustic central fire pit (being that of Ikara, Wilpena Pound), paying homage to the dreaming stories of the country. The ABC Range and Heysen Range are stretches of meticulously placed rocks which run outward from that towards Arkaba Creek, whilst the majestic Elder Range runs south toward the front of the homestead.&nbsp;The garden will provide another medium through which Wild Bush Luxury and Arkaba carry out their mission to not only conserve their environment but to inspire, educate and reconnect guests with the bush.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was pivotal, with sustainability in mind, that the Homestead Landscape design focused on utilising resources from around the property, to reflect the unique micro-environments at Arkaba Conservancy. Each geological range that is referenced is inspired by the rock formations of that specific range paired with the vegetation that is found in these landscapes. Guests will, literally, have a taste of what Arkaba has to offer in their back garden.<br>Melissa was particularly passionate about utilising native vegetation from Arkaba, propagating a variety of species to be planted out. This meant reintroducing specific natives like the Sturt Desert Rose (Gossypium sturtianum), which have not been seen on Arkaba for some time and encouraging indigenous threatened species like Slender Bell Fruit (Codonocarpus pyramidalis) to flourish.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not only will the garden represent a&nbsp;‘land that once was’&nbsp;but it will reflect the species that miraculously manage to thrive in this arid region of Australia. The benefit of utilising and encouraging the native flora from this region, means that it is naturally adapted to surviving with minimal rainfall – which is essential as we sit at the end (hopefully) of a five-year drought. This will ensure our garden is naturally sustainable and will need very little input from our human hands. To supplement this we pay homage to our farming heritage, utilising recycled farming materials throughout the design. From the path edging made out of old fencing pickets to old Cypress Pine fence posts as retaining walls for our outdoor dining space, ensuring the Arkaba Landscape project was truly designed with a holistic approach.<br>&nbsp;<br>It truly has been a huge effort by our guides, head chef and general manager at the homestead during these extraordinary times, to achieve this vision. This however is not the end of our gardens story, we are sure as the landscape naturally changes around us, our own backyard will evolve along with it and we are all looking forward to seeing what happens next!</p></p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9185</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</title>
		<link>/short-beaked-echidna-trains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Works]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nicola-Anne Jack recently joined our spirited field guiding team at Arkaba in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. She was warmly welcomed by a Short-beaked Echidna train sighting on her second day on the ground and she was kind enough to recall and share the moment with us. Here goes &#8230; It was always going to be [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/short-beaked-echidna-trains/">Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1182" class="elementor elementor-1182" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-3c3f0d87 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="3c3f0d87" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-340ff05e" data-id="340ff05e" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-78ce2805 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="78ce2805" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p style="text-align: center;">Nicola-Anne Jack recently joined our spirited field guiding team at Arkaba in South Australia’s Flinders Ranges. She was warmly welcomed by a Short-beaked Echidna train sighting on her second day on the ground and she was kind enough to recall and share the moment with us. Here goes &#8230;</p>
<div style="text-align: center;">It was always going to be a new and foreign experience heading to the Land Down Under to visit the Arkaba Conservancy in South Australia. Having spent the last three years working in the wilderness of Botswana the prospect of possibly relocating myself to the Australian Outback was somewhat daunting, especially with my limited knowledge on this incomparable environment with its extremely rare hopping fauna and fire loving flora.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Little did I realise that my visit to Arkaba had in stall for me one of the most fascinating and unique sightings I had and probably would ever see.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">The sighting occurred around 3pm as our Landcruiser ventured back from a visit to Elders Trail Camp.  As we drove the red sandstone slopes of white Cyprus Pine (Callitris glaucophylla) I was staring out the window when I noticed the movement of three small balls ambling in a wobbly line along the bottom of a steep slope. They walked in a trail one after the other, each following the first over the dusty soil. I surprisingly recognised this creature straight away, but I am sure this was only due to all the Australian documentaries I had recently watched! They were very peculiar looking with small rounded bodies covered with course hair and spines. Their snouts were prominent, slender and elongated. To me they looked like a hybrid of two familiar animals; a hedgehog and a very large shrew! As I stared on I could still not believe what I was seeing. My understanding was that this small marsupial which lays eggs – one of only five species in the world to do so – was a rare sighting.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Stop! Echidna’s, echidna’s!’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Brakes went on and both Bradley and Charlie heads whipped around searching the slopes to our left to try locate what I was seeing.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Are they in a line’, was Charlie’s first verbal response.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">In a line?  Since when do you ID an animal or spot an animal easier if it is in a line?</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘Yes?’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">‘It’s an echidna train!’</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">A what? I later discovered that an ‘echidna train’ is the term used to describe the mating behaviour of echidna’s (Tachyglossus aculeatus) during the winter season. During the mating season an oestrus female will release a pheromone which can attract up to ten males into close proximity. As each individual male finds the female it will follow her hence you get these trains of male echidna’s, in diminishing size order, following one female. Over several weeks the males will jostle each other out of the train until the most dominant suitor remains. This is the male which will mate with the female. It was unclear if our sighting was the tail end of this fascinating behaviour or only the beginning but as it stood at this point there were two males contending for the affection of the female.</div>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":9201,"sizeSlug":"full"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-group">
<div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<p class="has-text-align-center">We clambered out the car and quietly snuck up on this rare sight. I can safely say we did not do the best job of this as all three echidnas’ instantly responded to our approach. The female took full advantage of the situation and ambled up the slope away from us and both the males pursuing her. Maybe a welcome relief? The two remaining males demonstrated their best anti-predator behaviour which entailed using their robust digging claws to dig themselves into the soil beneath a large pine leaving only their exposed spiny backs as defence. We settle down to watch the two males, hoping they would feel relaxed enough to come out of their soil havens and walk around for us. As we waited Charlie informed us of some rare and specialised adaptions of this species including the presence of an egg tooth on the 10-day old naked translucent puggle (the name given to young echidna’s) and their ant and termite diet facilitated by a long sticky tongue. As we listened to Charlie the pair of males slowly emerged from their holes sniffing the air with their strange long snouts and then slowly (or maybe it was fast for an echidna) ambled away in opposite directions.   What a fascinating uniquely Australian experience! I am looking forward to the next one. To join us at <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba</a> for an outback Australian adventure with <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">purpose</a> call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Stay%20at%20Arkaba">email us</a> today.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:group --></p>
<p><!-- wp:group --></p>
<div class="wp-block-group">
<div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"> </div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:group --></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/short-beaked-echidna-trains/">Short-Beaked Echidna Trains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brush Tail Possum Spotted</title>
		<link>/brush-tail-possum-spotted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/finance/?p=1213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week was an incredibly exciting one for us with confirmation of what were once extinct Brush Tailed Possums (or Virlda in Adnyamathanha). Captured by one of our conservation cameras at our wildlife viewing hide, the blurry (and furry!) guy in the bottom right is being watched by a thirsty kangaroo. Brush tailed possums are believed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/brush-tail-possum-spotted/">Brush Tail Possum Spotted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Last week was an incredibly exciting one for us with confirmation of what were once extinct Brush Tailed Possums (or Virlda in Adnyamathanha). Captured by one of our conservation cameras at our <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wildlife viewing hide</a>, the blurry (and furry!) guy in the bottom right is being watched by a thirsty kangaroo.</p>
<div><img src="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/assets/blog/Brush%20Tail%20Possum/Possum.JPG" alt="" /></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Brush tailed possums are believed to have gone locally extinct in the 1940&#8217;s, with habitat degradation and predation by feral predators such as cats and foxes, being some of the suspected causes for its disappearance. Reintroduction alongside the Western Quoll (Idnya in Adnyamathanda) took place in Arkaba&#8217;s neighbouring Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park back in June 2015.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">With this individual safely being able to travel over 20km from the release site in search of food, water (and hopefully mating partners), it&#8217;s a significant sign good things are happening and our environment is recovering as a result <a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">conservation programs</a> being carried out by the Arkaba team. Conservation work that is actively supported by each and every guest who has ever experienced Wild Bush Luxury with us at Arkaba.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">To learn more about <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arkaba</a> or to experience conservation in action, call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Stay%20at%20Arkaba">email us</a> today.</div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/brush-tail-possum-spotted/">Brush Tail Possum Spotted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Favourite Watering Hole</title>
		<link>/our-favourite-watering-hole/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. The Hide at Arkaba is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed-vimeo wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Arkaba | Australian Natives at The Hide" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/283589764?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="1150" height="647" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">What kind of characters can you find at your local watering hole? The video above captures two of our favourite species, the Galah and the Australian Ringneck, in stunning color and clarity as they gathered for a drink and a bath. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkabas-hide/" target="_blank"><em>The Hide</em></a> at <a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/">Arkaba</a> is the favourite watering hole for many species of birds and mammals, from Red Kangaroos to Little Eagles, and it gives you a once-in-a-lifetime, up-close-and-personal experience with some of the outback’s wildest characters (sometimes even complete with a brawl!)<br> <br>Galahs are one of the most prominent and easily identifiable bird species in all of Australia. With their beautiful rose-colored bodies and noisy chattering, they are an unmistakable Australian icon. As seen here, this time of year you can find them flocking in large numbers before pairing off in the spring for mating. Similar to other bird species, Galahs pair for life and both sexes incubate eggs and care for young in the nest (cue: aw!). Once mating season is officially underway, Galahs can be found throughout Arkaba’s 60,000 acres nesting in tree hollows lined with their plucked down feathers. Though nationally Galahs have a high chick mortality rate (averaging 50% mortality per nest), we have seen an inspiring increase in chick survival at Arkaba as a direct benefit of feral cat management and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank">conservation</a>.<br> <br><strong>Did You Know:</strong> Though virtually every Australian can identify Galahs, very few can distinguish between males and females. The trick to identifying sex is in the EYE of the beholder – literally! Female Galahs have a light brown to pink iris, while males have a dark brown to black iris. Can you spot the sexes in this video?</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Arkaba is uniquely positioned on the cusp of the territory ranges of three species variations of Australian Ringneck Parrots. All three variations mate without discrimination and hybridize seamlessly, making for unique and exciting spottings for sharp-eyed bird watchers who can discern subtle plumage variations. Ringnecks are opportunists and will feed on whatever is available – fruits, seeds and even insects. Like Galahs, Ringnecks are readying to pair off for the mating season, where they too can be found in tree hollows. Luckily unlike Galahs, Ringnecks have impressive fledgling survival rate at around 75% per nest, and have also benefited from the feral cat management at Arkaba over the last nine years.<br>&nbsp;<br>The word “Arkaba” means “place of hidden water and place of plenty”. Like all the best, our hidden watering hole carefully carved out of Arkaba and Woolshed Creeks brings in a range of characters from the rowdy to the peaceful. You can of course indulge in a beverage of your choice and a spot of morning or afternoon tea at the Hide while rubbing shoulders and sharing a laugh with the locals at Arkaba’s watering hole. It’d be rude not to!<br>&nbsp;<br>To visit Arkaba&#8217;s watering hole yourself, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank">Wild Bush Luxury</a>&nbsp;Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20Arkaba!">email us</a>&nbsp;today!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/our-favourite-watering-hole/">Our Favourite Watering Hole</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9244</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</title>
		<link>/arkabas-hide-in-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our new hide is not only a place to see, but to watch wildlife and all the fascinating interactions that occur between species at&#160;Arkaba, our 60,000 acre private wildlife conservany in South Australia&#8217;s Ikara-Flinders Ranges.&#160; Common Wallaroos: (Macropus robustus erubescen) or Euros, belong to the Family Macropodidae. A very common sighting on Arkaba, this adult [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-hide-in-action/">Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Our new hide is not only a place to see, but to watch wildlife and all the fascinating interactions that occur between species at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba</a>, our 60,000 acre private wildlife conservany in South Australia&#8217;s Ikara-Flinders Ranges.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Common Wallaroos: (<em>Macropus robustus erubescen</em>) or Euros, belong to the Family Macropodidae. A very common sighting on Arkaba, this adult female was seen bringing her joey to drink at the hide. This little fellow would be approximately 10 months old and will be fully developed between 18-20 months. Even after this period of independence is reached, the youngster can maintain a very close relationship with its mother. It&#8217;s always fascinating to watch the interactions with other large Macropods such as the sub-adult Red Kangaroo in the background who was chased away on several occasions as he got too close to the joey.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Heading to the hide by Arkaba Creek for a spot of morning or afternoon tea is a chance to observe wildlife being wild.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you would like to speak to someone about our Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Arkaba%20Homestead%20and%20The%20Hide">email us</a>&nbsp;today</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="680" height="449" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9271" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449.jpg 680w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449-300x198.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkabas-Hide-Footer-680-x-449-610x403.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></figure>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-hide-in-action/">Arkaba&#8217;s Hide in Action</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</title>
		<link>/arkabas-little-eagle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This Little Eagle (Hieraaetus morphnoides) was spotted above&#160;Arkaba&#8217;s&#160;homestead garden. This individual might have been hunting rabbits, reptiles or even birds when field guide Charlie managed to snap this picture as it came down to land on an old fence post. This beautiful eagle, along with the larger and more commonly known Wedge-tailed eagle make up [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-little-eagle/">Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">This Little Eagle (Hieraaetus morphnoides) was spotted above&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba&#8217;s</a>&nbsp;homestead garden. This individual might have been hunting rabbits, reptiles or even birds when field guide Charlie managed to snap this picture as it came down to land on an old fence post. This beautiful eagle, along with the larger and more commonly known Wedge-tailed eagle make up the only two “booted” eagles in Australia, their feathered legs being one of the features that set them apart from other Australian Raptors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">New evidence suggests that Little Eagles migrate from South to North during the winter months, explaining why we tend to see them more frequently in the summer. One individual was recorded to have travelled as far as 3,000km in a season!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Nesting pairs of this very attractive eagle have been recorded across Arkaba, our private wildlife conservancy in&nbsp;South Australia&#8217;s Flinders Ranges over the past couple of years, with birds preferring to nest in dense, tree lined watercourses with large living trees. Arkaba will continue to be an attractive breeding ground for the Little Eagle, as&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/conservation-at-arkaba/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current and future conservation</a>&nbsp;projects continually improve the health of river red gum communities across the conservancy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you would like to speak to someone about the Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399&nbsp;to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury Specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20me%20more%20about%20Arkaba">email us</a>&nbsp;today.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="554" height="415" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9281" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2.jpg 554w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Little-Eagle-2-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></figure></div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkabas-little-eagle/">Arkaba&#8217;s Little Eagle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9280</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
