<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Wild Bush People &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/wild-bush-people/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Wild Bush Luxury</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 06:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/cropped-Arkaba-Walk-Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Wild Bush People &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184390017</site>	<item>
		<title>Evolution or Insect?</title>
		<link>/evolution-or-insect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom. Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9427" class="elementor elementor-9427" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-53f8da9 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="53f8da9" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-dd966f9" data-id="dd966f9" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-18b3892 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="18b3892" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p><!-- wp:video {"id":8640} --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:video --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"center"} --></p>
<p>Whilst out on the Southern end of Arkaba, field guide Melissa Robertson noticed a curious phenomenon. When inspecting multiple Acacia Tetragonophylla (Dead Finish) in bloom, excitedly she noticed that the trees were throwing the odd red wattle blossom.</p>
<p>Still in correspondence with the SA State Herbarium, the reasoning behind this rare anomaly is still unknown, however two theories have been posed; an evolutionary mutation perhaps, producing sports e.g. different flower colour, from genetic changes or the flower heads could have been attacked or galled by an insect such as a thirp or wasp, who have had a long evolution between the gall maker and the plant.</p>
<p><div class="envira-gallery-feed-output"><img class="envira-gallery-feed-image" tabindex="0" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_8220-1.jpg" title="Acacia Tetragonophylla" alt="" /></div></p>
<p>A very exciting and stunning find for us on Arkaba, we shall be watching how they evolve!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/evolution-or-insect/">Evolution or Insect?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</title>
		<link>/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After 5 years of drought, Arkaba Homestead has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots. It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>After 5 years of drought, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank">Arkaba Homestead</a> has taken a new and more sustainable approach to its homestead landscape, embarking upon a journey to take its immediate surroundings back to its indigenous roots.<br> <br>It has been many years now that our traditional lawned oasis has struggled through a lack of water and frequent mobs of hungry kangaroos, so the change was in order. Our main objective was to ensure the Arkaba garden reflected our greater purpose, to conserve and encourage our natural environment to flourish, with a little flare of course. As the long standing homestead fence was pulled down, local designer and Arkaba field guide, Melissa Robertson, was tasked with finding a way to bring the Arkaba ethos right to the homestead’s back door.<br> <br>With a Bachelor Degree in Design Arts and armed with 8 years’ experience running her successful design business, I Am Melissa, in Melbourne, it was only fitting that Melissa Robertson took on the role of Arkaba Landscape Designer. Melissa strived to create a design with meaning and greater purpose, taking her inspiration from the land, to mirror the surrounds of the stunning Flinders Ranges, whilst creating a sustainable landscape.</p> <img loading="lazy" width="300" height="248" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Mel-300x248.jpg" alt="" style="font-size: inherit;"></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><p>Arkaba’s newly designed garden is modelled off the aerial view of the vast ranges that tower around Arkaba and included the well-known geological anomaly, Wilpena Pound. As you walk out into the back garden you are greeted with a rustic central fire pit (being that of Ikara, Wilpena Pound), paying homage to the dreaming stories of the country. The ABC Range and Heysen Range are stretches of meticulously placed rocks which run outward from that towards Arkaba Creek, whilst the majestic Elder Range runs south toward the front of the homestead.&nbsp;The garden will provide another medium through which Wild Bush Luxury and Arkaba carry out their mission to not only conserve their environment but to inspire, educate and reconnect guests with the bush.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was pivotal, with sustainability in mind, that the Homestead Landscape design focused on utilising resources from around the property, to reflect the unique micro-environments at Arkaba Conservancy. Each geological range that is referenced is inspired by the rock formations of that specific range paired with the vegetation that is found in these landscapes. Guests will, literally, have a taste of what Arkaba has to offer in their back garden.<br>Melissa was particularly passionate about utilising native vegetation from Arkaba, propagating a variety of species to be planted out. This meant reintroducing specific natives like the Sturt Desert Rose (Gossypium sturtianum), which have not been seen on Arkaba for some time and encouraging indigenous threatened species like Slender Bell Fruit (Codonocarpus pyramidalis) to flourish.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not only will the garden represent a&nbsp;‘land that once was’&nbsp;but it will reflect the species that miraculously manage to thrive in this arid region of Australia. The benefit of utilising and encouraging the native flora from this region, means that it is naturally adapted to surviving with minimal rainfall – which is essential as we sit at the end (hopefully) of a five-year drought. This will ensure our garden is naturally sustainable and will need very little input from our human hands. To supplement this we pay homage to our farming heritage, utilising recycled farming materials throughout the design. From the path edging made out of old fencing pickets to old Cypress Pine fence posts as retaining walls for our outdoor dining space, ensuring the Arkaba Landscape project was truly designed with a holistic approach.<br>&nbsp;<br>It truly has been a huge effort by our guides, head chef and general manager at the homestead during these extraordinary times, to achieve this vision. This however is not the end of our gardens story, we are sure as the landscape naturally changes around us, our own backyard will evolve along with it and we are all looking forward to seeing what happens next!</p></p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-towards-a-sustainable-and-beautiful-future/">Working towards a sustainable and beautiful future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9185</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outback Adventure</title>
		<link>/outback-adventure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The journey started weeks before I arrived in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges for the Arkaba walk. The excitement of the adventure that I was about to embark on. Leaving my busy city life, I packed my bags and head for the outback to reconnect. As I stepped off our private plane in Hawker, I took in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-adventure/">Outback Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">The journey started weeks before I arrived in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges for the Arkaba walk. The excitement of the adventure that I was about to embark on. Leaving my busy city life, I packed my bags and head for the outback to reconnect.</p>
<p>As I stepped off our private plane in Hawker, I took in a deep breath smelling the fresh country air. Taking in my surroundings, I had never seen such vibrant colours of earthly oranges and reds. There was no denying that I was in the Australian outback. We enjoyed our continental breakfast as we learnt about the land on our way to Wilpena for the start of our walk.</p>
<p>After a few hours of walking through the changing scenery of Wilpena Pound, we approached the edge of Arkaba Conservancy. A birder got our attention making a gesture to come over quietly. Over on the rock face he points out the movement and handed me his binoculars. It&#8217;s a yellow-footed rock wallaby. How exciting! I knew these guys were near threatened so this sighting was a true blessing.</p>
<p>We were welcomed into camp with a warm smile, a face towel and a delicious fresh juice. The perfect combination to feel right at home. I was way too eager to head to bed that evening. Taking our guides advice, I pulled my swag bed from under cover exposing it directly under the night sky. Upon gazing up, I was instantly in awe, the abundance of stars was absolutely breathtaking. The peace and serenity being a true luxury only possible to experience in such a remote location.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Even though I have grown up in Australia, there is still something special about seeing kangaroos amongst the acient landscape in the outback. We made a game of guessing which type of kangaroo we were spotting. We eventually learnt to tell the difference between euros, western greys and reds.. with the help of our guide of course.</p>
<p>Coming over Arkaba hill on the final day with the homestead in sight brought on a range of emotions. On one hand we were all wishing the walk to be longer, on the other we were so excited to see where we were going to call home for the evening. Waiting with a fresh juice, closely followed by a G &amp; T our guides did not disappoint with a warm welcome back to the homestead.</p>
<p>Spending four days walking with the group, we got to know each other pretty well. Everyone had their own story what brought them to experiencing the Arkaba walk. Some had dreamed of visiting the Flinders since they were young and for others it was serendipitous. What we all left there with was the mutual feeling that there was something so uniquely special about Arkaba and we will remember the experience for a life time.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-adventure/">Outback Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outback Art &#038; Ode to Wildlife</title>
		<link>/outback-art-ode-to-wildlife/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9258</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rosemary Woodford-Ganf is a South Australian based wildlife artist, whose skills flourished while living in Africa, where her father was a vet and spent his time researching wildlife diseases in Uganda. Since the early 1970s Rosie has lived in Australia and devoted her skills to the painting and sculpting of Australia&#8217;s native wildlife. Her artwork [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-art-ode-to-wildlife/">Outback Art &#038; Ode to Wildlife</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Rosemary Woodford-Ganf is a South Australian based wildlife artist, whose skills flourished while living in Africa, where her father was a vet and spent his time researching wildlife diseases in Uganda. Since the early 1970s Rosie has lived in Australia and devoted her skills to the painting and sculpting of Australia&#8217;s native wildlife. Her artwork adorns many of the walls at Arkaba and her creative mind is behind the recycled and bush inspired decor at our <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/arkaba-homestead/" target="_blank">Arkaba Homestead</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9260" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-391x260.jpg 391w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-610x407.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board-1500x1000.jpg 1500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Side-board.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In 1974 Rosie migrated to Australia and settled in Adelaide where her skills in wildlife drawing found her commissioned in 1976 to illustrate a three volume set of limited edition books called&nbsp;<em>&#8220;The Marsupials of Australia&#8221;&nbsp;</em>the third volume of which contained the Kangaroos, Wallabies and Rat-Kangaroos with text written by the late John Henry Calaby. Limited edition prints of this volume now hang on the walls of the guestrooms at Arkaba Homestead. The three volume project would ultimately take more than 15 years to publish, with Tim Flannery stepping in to take over as author of the final volume, after Calaby&#8217;s passing.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">On completion of the books Rosie holds the exclusive title of being the only person to illustrate every living Australian marsupial, an unprecedented achievement unlikely to be repeated by anyone, much less in the same extraordinary detail. These illustrations have since been published as a single volume with a new text by Dr. Christopher Dickman, called &#8220;A Fragile Balance, the extraordinary story of Australian marsupials&#8221;. This book won the Whitley Award for the best publication on the natural history of Australian animals, in 2008.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">When the heritage homestead on Arkaba was restored, updating to modern conveniences, keeping a sense of history and connection to the land was of the essence. Who better to assist in providing the quintessential Australian charm than Rosie, who has lovingly crafted bedheads fashioned from recycled fence posts and fleeces. Gumnut tassel curtain ties and floor lights made from early explorer&#8217;s tripod theodolites. A wonderful selection of her wildlife paintings take pride of place on the walls throughout the homestead and are admired by Wild Bush Luxury guests from all over the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you&#8217;d like to experience&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arkabaconservancy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba</a>&nbsp;and see Rosie&#8217;s work for yourself, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury specialist or&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20me%20more%20about%20the%20Wild%20Bush%20Luxury%20experience%20at%20Arkaba">email&nbsp;</a>us today.&nbsp;</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/outback-art-ode-to-wildlife/">Outback Art &#038; Ode to Wildlife</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9258</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arkaba Through Adnamatna Eyes</title>
		<link>/arkaba-through-adnamatna-eyes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 07:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A walk with Pauline McKenzie is an opportunity to connect you with stories of Adnamatna people, Australia’s first people who have long looked after the landscape and wildlife of South Australia’s Ikara-Flinders Ranges. Adnamatna people come from tens of thousands of years as an oral culture and this has made them wonderful story tellers. Pauline [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkaba-through-adnamatna-eyes/">Arkaba Through Adnamatna Eyes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">A walk with Pauline McKenzie is an opportunity to connect you with stories of Adnamatna people, Australia’s first people who have long looked after the landscape and wildlife of South Australia’s Ikara-Flinders Ranges. Adnamatna people come from tens of thousands of years as an oral culture and this has made them wonderful story tellers. Pauline is a living library of her ancient Adnamatna lifestyle. Born in Hawker, she spent much of her childhood on country just north of Arkaba and, like most indigenous people of a certain age, has a connection with the land that emanates from long before any European explorers or settlers appeared.&nbsp;<br>Pauline lives locally in Hawker and is one of few people who still speaks the Adnamatna language fluently.&nbsp;She spends a large portion of her time teaching cultural stories and language (Yura Muda) at the Hawker area school and is determined that Adnamatna stories and her culture are passed on.&nbsp;Her stories of the land and her personal story growing up as a person in ‘white’ Australia provide a glimpse into Australia’s Aboriginal history and the issues that confront Aboriginal society today.&nbsp;<br><br>Arkaba through Adnamatna Eyes is a shared two hour experience costing $150 per person request in advance paid locally operating with a minimum of two people.&nbsp;To add this experience to your booking please email&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com">arkaba@wildbushluxury.com</a>&nbsp;or call 1300 790 561 today.&nbsp;</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/arkaba-through-adnamatna-eyes/">Arkaba Through Adnamatna Eyes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9277</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Greatness of Guides &#8211; a Wild Bush Luxury Given</title>
		<link>/the-greatness-of-guides-a-wild-bush-luxury-given/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My name is Amy and I’ve worked in Wild Bush Luxury’s reservations team now for over a year and half. In April, I experienced The Arkaba Walk and despite originating from South Australia and having visited The Ikara-Flinders Ranges several times in my life, my experience of The Arkaba Walk was genuinely one of my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-greatness-of-guides-a-wild-bush-luxury-given/">The Greatness of Guides &#8211; a Wild Bush Luxury Given</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">My name is Amy and I’ve worked in Wild Bush Luxury’s reservations team now for over a year and half. In April, I experienced The Arkaba Walk and despite originating from South Australia and having visited The Ikara-Flinders Ranges several times in my life, my experience of The Arkaba Walk was genuinely one of my favourite travel experiences ever. I was in such a need of an escape from the hustle and bustle of Sydney and the business of everyday life that I was literally bursting to ‘go bush’. I was impressed of course by the indescribable beauty of the area but what really stood out for me and has become a source of pride was the greatness of our Wild Bush Luxury guides.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">After checking in at 6am for our flight to the gateway of The Flinders Ranges, I saw many people that looked dressed to walk and I wondered if any were the group I might be walking with. Turns out there were 6 walkers on my flight. We didn’t know each other and the continental breakfast that is served as part of the package ex Adelaide was a polite affair, full of anticipation, expectation and trepidation of being with the group for 60 hours. Enter Meghan and Sam, our respective guide and camp support crew for the walk. A wave of warmth radiated from both, clear excited eyes, big smiles, both imparting an overwhelming sense of willingness and eagerness to take great care of us and share Arkaba and a bit of themselves; the Aboriginal history, the pastoral history, the geological history and of course, all the many wonderful activities that they undertake to conserve the environment.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="225" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Amy-and-Guides.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9285"/></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">The Arkaba Walk operates with a minimum of 2 and maximum of 10 walkers and as you can imagine, walkers come from all walks of life, diverse backgrounds and experiences and have assorted reasons as to how they’ve ended up choosing to spend time on the Arkaba Walk. A common thread is a love of the natural environment and to be immersed within it. With many different personalities to engage with, introverts and extroverts and some in between, Meghan and Sam did such a wonderful job of sharing their knowledge of the area, flora and fauna but in a conversational way that always invited inclusion. Their ability to wind and weave joy and wonder, laughs and jokes, education and knowledge were so seamless and always enjoyable.<br>&nbsp;Arkaba Walk guides work hard but seem to whistle as they work (or in Sam’s case, sing!). Working as a team, 1 guide escorts the walking group over the 3 days and the camp support guide meets the group at the end of each day. Our guides ensure that luggage is transported between the camps, the beautiful star beds are all set up, a 3 course dinner or hot breakfast is enjoyed, your wine or coffee cup replenished, dishes are done, answering or researching questions that have arisen during the day (they never forget!), hosting meal times or warming water to perfect temperatures for the very unique bush showers. So much goes on behind the scenes but the wondrous thing about being on the walk is you just don’t know – amazing Wild Bush Luxury experiences keep being delivered over the 3 days but are never expected, they are however always appreciated. Needs and wants are met just before you realised that you might need or want something.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">What I truly loved and something that we consistently get reviews about is the quality of our guides. I found our guides really love their job, the surrounding environment, the team they work with and their leader, lodge manager Brendon and Arkaba’s owner Charles Carlow. There is a consistency of passion, vision and energy throughout the team that shines so bright.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="225" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Group-of-Walkers.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9287"/></figure></div>



<p>After returning from The Arkaba Walk, I am keen to speak with anyone about it because I know whole heartedly that the experience starts with me and our reservations team and ends with the final wave from our incredible Arkaba team, who deliver and exceed our promises. I know that the experience we are selling is something to look forward to and an experience to be cherished. It’s hard for me not to spoil the secrets of the many Wild Bush Luxury touches that surprise along the walk out of sheer enthusiasm! I feel, above all, proud to be part of a team that truly cares about what they do and the way they make people feel.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">It’s true to say that our wonderful walking group, guides included, met as strangers but left as firm friends who had a truly wonderful, stimulating, replenishing, educational, memorable and enjoyable shared experience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you have any queries about the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.arkabawalk.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arkaba Walk</a>, or any other Wild Bush Luxury experiences, I’d love to help. Get in touch at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com">arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com</a>&nbsp;or call 1300 790 561. Make sure you grab a drink, settle in and get comfy!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Amy&nbsp;</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-greatness-of-guides-a-wild-bush-luxury-given/">The Greatness of Guides &#8211; a Wild Bush Luxury Given</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9284</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hanging up our Shirts</title>
		<link>/hanging-up-our-shirts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9289</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What a delightful way to reflect on the Arkaba Walk season that was, with this picture of a rainbow hugging our Elder Range. Come and learn about some of the exciting things that have happened in our region: Lonely Planet has named South Australia as one of the Top 5 regions of the World to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hanging-up-our-shirts/">Hanging up our Shirts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">What a delightful way to reflect on the Arkaba Walk season that was, with this picture of a rainbow hugging our Elder Range. Come and learn about some of the exciting things that have happened in our region:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Lonely Planet has named South Australia as one of the Top 5 regions of the World to visit in 2017 and our region, the Ikara-Flinders Ranges, certainly delivered. We’ve loved being able to share this remarkable landscape with more people, from all walks of life and every corner of the globe, than ever before. The sky has seen a noticable increase in raptor activity with a new active eagle nest very close to the Arkaba Homestead.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">As many of you may have noted, we have experienced a drier season than usual, leading to suberb walking conditions and unbelievably starry nights that stretch endlesslyacross the sky, uninterrupted with your best viewpoint being all wrapped up in our signature star beds.&nbsp;<br>This year an Ikara-Flinders Ranges rock shelter had a chance discovery making it the oldest known site of Aboriginal settlement in arid Australia. The discovery revealed settlement in the region existed a staggering 10,000 years earlier than previously thought and serves as the first reliably dated evidence of human interaction with megafauna! We’re reminded again just how young we are, a short walk through Arkaba&#8217;s landscape clearly illustrates the changes of time the Ikara-Flinders Ranges have seen, the colour of the rocks under our feet, each coming from a different location, a different millennia telling a different story. If only those big old River Red Gum trees could talk!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Walkers are learning how we are breathing native life back into Arkaba. Now 7 years in to our active conservation program, we can see how the land is responding, regenerating, and how native wildlife is returning all the time and in greater numbers. Guests are learning why conservation and saving Australia&#8217;s biodiversity matters, and why our future delivering quality wildlife experiences depends on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">To all of our friends and family of the Arkaba Walk &#8211; Brendon, Charlie and the entire team would like to thank you for walking with us and allowing us to share our love for this incredible place in outback South Australia, Arkaba in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges. Please get in touch any time on&nbsp;<a href="mailto:arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Arkaba%20Walk%202018">arkabawalk@wildbushluxury.com</a>, we&#8217;d love to hear from you. See you for more wilderness walking from 22 March 2018!</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hanging-up-our-shirts/">Hanging up our Shirts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9289</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Harry met Arkaba</title>
		<link>/when-harry-met-arkaba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As I sat dressed in what I had assumed was perfect walking gear, I began to question whether or not I was truly prepared. I am a fan of a walk, but hadn’t really done anything that required walking gear since school camps. At this stage, being propelled across the York peninsula, it was far [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/when-harry-met-arkaba/">When Harry met Arkaba</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">As I sat dressed in what I had assumed was perfect walking gear, I began to question whether or not I was truly prepared. I am a fan of a walk, but hadn’t really done anything that required walking gear since school camps. At this stage, being propelled across the York peninsula, it was far too late to make any changes so I was resolved to conquering the Flinders Ranges in my current state. <br><br>Upon arrival to the Arkaba Homestead, 8 travelers with a hint of trepidation, flocked around morning tea and had a thorough re-evaluation of the number of layers required. Bags were repacked and readjusted and before long we were 8 trepid hikers taking on the ranges with our knowledgeable guide leading the way. Not thirty minutes later I felt my Fitbit buzz alerting me to the fact that I had already reached my daily goal. Unable to sit down and relish in my triumph, I persevered through the groves of gum trees and forests of Mallee gums each while I grew increasingly enamored. Upon summiting at Bridle Gap we had our first true “WOW” Moment. Looking back over the vast expanse of land we had covered we felt accomplished, looking forward to the rolling hills and outcrops we thought “Challenge accepted”. 22,000 steps later we walked (read stumbled) into camp where I was handed chilled facial towel to wash my face, it felt like the greatest luxury imaginable. A tour of the thoughtfully designed Blacks Gap camp completed I raced to shower in true wild bush luxury style, open to the elements with an incredible view of Wilpena Pound as the sun set on it. Photos (mine at least) certainly don’t do it any justice. After a few fireside wines, a delicious meal and a brief for the coming days walk we each retreated back to our swag decks for a night out under the stars.  </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="300" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-300x300.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9294" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View-610x610.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Day-2-View.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Hours later I woke to the rising sun, and a couple of kangaroos bounding passed my deck. Yep, I definitely wasn’t at home. A leisurely morning passed and soon we were traversing creek beds lined with writhing river redgums. Amongst these creeks where huge slate walls which so clearly showed the tectonic movement and changes our ancient landscape has been through. It’s at this point we all started to pay more attention and notice little things like the colour of the rocks under our feet, each one from a different location, a different millennia telling a different story. My Grandfather’s motto “It really makes you think” rang true in my head. It would be hard to pick a favorite spot or moment from our second days walk, but summiting the red range and looking back on how far we’d come and looking towards the multicolored elder range (with the added promise of our camp for the night) was a pretty special moment. After passing through a forest of Xanthorrhoea, sampling their sweet nectar, we made it to camp where that chilled facial towel hadn’t lost any of its luster.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">It’s at this point, sitting on my swag deck with no one and no structure in sight, I realise I get it. I’ve truly become captivated by the story of our land, by the beauty of my surroundings and of the importance of protecting and conserving our environment. That night after more fireside wines (read drink till your joints aren’t sore) and a delicious meal I lie under the clearest stars I have ever seen, staring straight into the Milky Way and wouldn’t you know it there’s a meteor shower. I counted four shooting stars before my eyelids finally won their battle and forced me to sleep.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Xanthorea.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9297" width="315" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Xanthorea.jpg 480w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Xanthorea-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Xanthorea-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9295" width="315" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range-610x610.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Elder-Range.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">It was with almost a heavy heart that we set off for the last time towards the homestead, a few “but can’t we stay one more night?!” were thrown around half-jokingly-but-mostly-seriously. As we crossed through forests of cypress pines, carpets of moss and lichen the conversations shifted. We had always been appreciative and enthralled by the nature around us but now with the walk coming to a close we wanted every last drop of information we could get about every bird, every plant and every range.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">After crossing the manicured lawn of the Homestead and settling into our comfortable Homestead Rooms we enjoyed an exceptional meal paired with delicious wines, but what really stood out was the atmosphere. 8 Weary walkers felt absolutely at home.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">It is hard to express the sense of accomplishment and excitement you feel at the end of the walk, it is really something that you have to experience. But after leaving the homestead and looking back towards the ranges, I couldn’t help but feel like I’d do it all again in a heartbeat.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">I would be delighted to help connect you with Arkaba and the fascinating stories of our land, so please get in touch at <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com">arkaba@wildbushluxury.com</a> or by calling 1300 790 561. I can&#8217;t wait to hear from you!<br>Harry</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/when-harry-met-arkaba/">When Harry met Arkaba</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9292</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
