<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Wild Bush Luxury</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:57:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/cropped-Arkaba-Walk-Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; The Arkaba Walk</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184390017</site>	<item>
		<title>Eradicat Program</title>
		<link>/eradicat-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 05:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4"></video></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">At the beginning of June 2020, Arkaba lodge manager Charlie Eager and field guide Alex Nielson joined conservation land managers and ecologists from across South Australia in partnership with Operation Bounceback. Bounceback is a project that has been working on landscape scale restoration in the Flinders Ranges for decades. This specific collaboration was to prepare 30 000 sausages for the 2020 eradicat feral cat bait trial. The eradicate programme is an attempt to control feral cat populations in the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park and the adjoining Arkaba Conservancy. Arkaba has been involved in this trial for the past few years. If deemed successful, this new technique of cat control will be rolled out across the state and potentially even country wide. Arkaba Conservancy (64 000 acres) acts as an important southern corridor for the Ikara-Flinders Ranges National Park, with the Conservancy’s conservation efforts partnering with those of the National Park to increase the habitat area and viability for local populations of threatened native species.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In 2014, Idnya (Western Quoll) and Virlda (Brush tailed Possum) where reintroduced into the Flinders Ranges. Both mammals had become locally extinct due to the compounding effects of habitat destruction and the arrival of feral carnivore species (cats and foxes). On Akaba, feral cat management has and continues to involve cage trapping, spotlight shooting and the control of feral rabbit populations. These efforts whilst playing an important role are yet to deliver a knockout blow to local feral cat populations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Historically, baiting has not been an overly successful control method for cats as they prefer to catch their own prey and consume them differently to feral foxes and dogs. The eradicate baiting trials have now been ongoing for a number of years in an attempt to investigate the effectiveness of a 1080 (toxin derived from native flora) sausage bait that has been specifically designed to be more appealing to feral cats.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Prior to the baits being dropped across the National Park and Arkaba, feral cats and Western Quolls have been caught and collared (with radio collars) to monitor their movements as well as the effect of the bait. Past years have shown that the bait has been highly effective on cats with no known deaths to the quolls, who like other native animals have a natural evolved tolerance to the native toxin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">The current results of the eradicate programme for 2020 have shown that 4 of the 9 collared cats have died and none of the 16 collared quolls have been affected, this is certainly deemed as a success.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Whilst participating in the baiting day, Arkaba staff had the unique opportunity to see three Western quolls be released after capture and collaring (as per the video where Charlie Eager is release one of the quolls). Seeing these beautiful and rare native marsupials bounce off through the bush was an experience that we hope with continued cat control all future visitors and generations will one day have the chance to enjoy.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/eradicat-program/">Eradicat Program</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/quoll-video-1.mp4" length="9187499" type="video/mp4" />

		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</title>
		<link>/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photogarphy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.goodlayers.com/infinite/homepages/onepage/?p=1184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past 36 years Richard I’Anson has travelled the world amassing a substantial and compelling collection of images of people and places in more than 90 countries on all seven continents. He is one of five photographers selected for the National Geographic Channel television series Tales by Light now showing on Netflix. We asked him why keeps coming [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/">Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">Over the past 36 years <a href="https://richardianson.com/2013/05/22/bamurru-photo-safari-images/">Richard I’Anson</a> has travelled the world amassing a substantial and compelling collection of images of people and places in more than 90 countries on all seven continents. He is one of five photographers selected for the National Geographic Channel television series <em>Tales by Light</em> now showing on Netflix. We asked him why keeps coming back to Bamurru Plains. Here’s what he said;</p>
<p><strong>You can’t predict what’s going to happen or script settings when photographing wildlife in the wild. Can you share any hot tips in getting good wildlife shots in such a dynamic environment?</strong></p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Concentrate your efforts to early morning and late afternoon when wildlife is most active.</p>
<p>Make sure you’ve got the right gear for the subject matter you’re photographing, the location and what you’re hoping to achieve. Typically, a DSLR with a telephoto zoom is the way to go. You’ll need a lens with a focal length of at least 300mm and for birds at least 500mm. A 100-400mm zoom lens is great, add a 1.4x extender and you’ve got a range from 100-560mm.</p>
<p>Make sure you’ve practiced, and ideally perfected, your technique as the most interesting moments of action, such as birds taking off or landing, happen very quickly and you don’t want to be messing around with your gear at the crucial moment.</p>
<p>A good guide, and in the case of Bamurru a good airboat driver, are crucial to getting you into the best position by considering the direction of the light, the background and the potential for action. Let alone spotting potential subjects in the first place.</p>
<p>Finally, you need to be patient. Wildlife shots that go beyond the simple identification picture take time and commitment, so patience is a key part of wildlife photographers’ makeup. But when it all comes together the hours of watching, waiting and practicing will be well rewarded with memorable, and often, one-off images.</p>
<p><strong>You’re a world traveller through and through. Can you share your thoughts on what makes Bamurru unique and worth travelling across the country, or indeed the world, to experience?</strong></p>
<p>It is just that! Bamurru is unique. There is no where else like it. The outback location, the ambience of the lodge and safari cabins, the great food and the adventure of getting about the floodplains on airboats. And that’s even before you start considering the wonderful photography on offer every time you step outside.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a favourite moment from your last safari?</strong></p>
<p>There are always so many favourite moments. The lilies were absolutely incredible this year, I’ve never seen them so dense. We came across a comb-crested jacana, one of the hardest birds to photograph, protecting the eggs that she had laid on a waterlily leaf, so she wasn’t going anywhere. And a perennial favourite is heading back to the lodge on an airboat at sunset sipping a red wine and reflecting on how amazing it is just to be there.</p>
<p><strong>If these kind of group trips aren’t usually your thing, would you recommend giving this one five days of your precious time?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely! Bamurru is special and the photography safari is pretty special too, which is why we have so many returning guests. You’ll be joining a small group of enthusiast photographers keen to improve their photography skills in a unique setting offering so many opportunities to photograph landscapes, wildlife, birds and indigenous culture that you’ll probably want to return too. And I’ve never yet had a group up at Bamurru that isn’t great company.</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">If you&#8217;d like to speak to someone about our <a href="https://www.bamurruplains.com/top-end-wilderness-photo-safari/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Top End Wilderness Photo Safari</u></a> with Canon Master Richard I’Anson 27 April &#8211; 1 May 2019 call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a <a href="http://www.wildbushluxury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild Bush Luxury</a> specialist or <a href="mailto:bamurru@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Tell%20Me%20More%20About%20the%20Richard%20I%27Anson%20Photo%20Safari!">email us</a> today.</div>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/richard-ianson-and-bamurru-plains/">Why Canon Master Photographer Richard I’Anson keeps returning to Bamurru Plains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Great Gear for a Great Walk</title>
		<link>/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Bush Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since 1930,&#160;Paddy Pallin&#160;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since 1930,&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.paddypallin.com.au/" target="_blank">Paddy Pallin</a>&nbsp;has been enabling and inspiring Australian adventure seekers to get outside and explore both nationally and worldwide. With a firm grasp of company history rooted in Paddy’s own sense of adventure, we continuously look to seek out and supply outdoor enthusiasts with the lightest and most advanced gear from the world’s leading brands.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9236" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Photo-by-Lachlan-Gardiner-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Photo by Lachlan Gardiner</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy was a gear maker and innovator. Through each generation of business, Paddy Pallin’s products have kept people comfortable and safe so you have the confidence to head out and explore the world.</p>



<p>Frank Austin Pallin, who we all know and love as “Paddy”, was always at the forefront of Australian conservation. His efforts were further cemented in launching the Paddy Pallin Foundation, which began simply as an informal way to give funds to suitable causes, and to educate those who had an active interest in the environment. Whether they loved plants and animals, bushwalking, canyoning, skiing, climbing or camping – Paddy and his customers at the time knew we had something on our hands worth protecting.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9233" width="750" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin.jpg 950w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-300x91.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-768x234.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Frank-Pallin-610x186.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 950px) 100vw, 950px" /><figcaption>Founder, Frank Austin Pallin</figcaption></figure>



<p>Since its inception in 1975, The Paddy Pallin Foundation has supported a myriad of environmental campaigns including the Tasmanian Franklin River Fight, the conservation of the Glossy Black Cockatoo and the Great Koala National Park. Over the years, Paddy Pallin (in conjunction with the Paddy Pallin Foundation) has partnered with various environmental conservation groups to help develop initiatives to promote and conserve our natural Australian environments and protect our native animal and plant species.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Franklin-River.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9234" width="750" height="400"/><figcaption>Franklin River, Tasmania. Photo by Mark W, a winner of Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest to raise funds and awareness for the &#8220;Give a Dam&#8221; campaign in NSW</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="750" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9235" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-300x160.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Great-Koala-National-Park-610x325.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><figcaption>Great Koala National Park, one of the various conservation initiatives Paddy Pallin has committed to supporting</figcaption></figure>



<p>In support of these environmental values, Paddy Pallin has committed to donating 20 cents to an environmental cause every time one of their customers says “no” to a shopping bag. This initiative spans the country, with customers from coast to coast finding creative ways to haul their gear out of the store!&nbsp; Last year alone, with the help of sustainably minded customers Paddy Pallin was able to divert over 37,000 shopping bags from landfill. This year, Paddy Pallin is supporting a conservation project titled ‘Protect Australia’ that strives to safeguard Australia’s native plant and animal species.</p>



<p>Seeking out community initiatives to support, Paddy Pallin gets involved on both a nation wide and small local scale. Most recently, Paddy Pallin put its forces behind the Wild Rivers campaign, now going by the name ‘Give a Dam’. Raising both funds and awareness through a photo contest to show case the location’s natural beauty, this campaign focused on protecting the greater Blue Mountains area from flooding due to the proposed raising of the Warragamba Dam.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9237" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest-610x915.jpg 610w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Wild-Rivers-Photo-Contest.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption>Photo from Paddy Pallin&#8217;s Wild Rivers Photo Contest. Photo by Joel J.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Paddy Pallin as an organisation prides itself on offering the highest quality outdoor gear from around the world that’s brought to you with reliable, expert customer service and intertwined environmental priorities allowing consumers to have a voice and an impact with their purchases.</p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/great-gear-for-a-great-walk/">Great Gear for a Great Walk</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Capturing Arkaba &#038; Lake Eyre Photo Safari</title>
		<link>/capturing-arkaba-lake-eyre-photo-safari/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Pritchett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Charge your camera and pack your safari gear! Kati Thanda Lake-Eyre has been transformed bringing life to South Australia&#8217;s parched salt pans and desert country. We&#8217;re celebrating with this five-day photographic safari led by Canon Master and author of Lonely Planet&#8217;s Guide to Travel Photography, Richard I&#8217;Anson on 29 July &#8211; 2 August 2018. It&#8217;s your rare opportunity to capture [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/capturing-arkaba-lake-eyre-photo-safari/">Capturing Arkaba &#038; Lake Eyre Photo Safari</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Charge your camera and pack your safari gear! Kati Thanda Lake-Eyre has been transformed bringing life to South Australia&#8217;s parched salt pans and desert country. We&#8217;re celebrating with this five-day photographic safari led by Canon Master and author of Lonely Planet&#8217;s Guide to Travel Photography, Richard I&#8217;Anson on 29 July &#8211; 2 August 2018. It&#8217;s your rare opportunity to capture the surreal beauty of water-soaked Lake Eyre, Arkaba&#8217;s prehistoric outback landscape and abundant wildlife in all-inclusive luxury. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="600" height="400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkaba-and-Richard-IAnson.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9266" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkaba-and-Richard-IAnson.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkaba-and-Richard-IAnson-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Arkaba-and-Richard-IAnson-391x260.jpg 391w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8220;Im very much looking forward to introducing a small group of photography enthusiasts to Arkaba. This special place provides the perfect base for classic outback landscape and wildlife photography. We&#8217;ll have the chance to capture Lake Eyre which has been high on my Australian shot list for years, and even better with water in it! Photographing this occasional natural event at a famously remote and iconic spot is a privilege&#8221; &#8211; Richard I&#8217;Anson.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you&#8217;d like to speak to someone about our Wild Bush Luxury experience at Arkaba, please call (02) 9571 6399 to speak with a Wild Bush Luxury specialist or <a href="mailto:arkaba@wildbushluxury.com?subject=Capturing%20Arkaba%20and%20Lake%20Eyre%20Photographic%20Safari">email </a>us today. </p>
<span class="et_bloom_bottom_trigger"></span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/capturing-arkaba-lake-eyre-photo-safari/">Capturing Arkaba &#038; Lake Eyre Photo Safari</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Arkaba Walk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9265</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
